<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<courses>
    <course academic_year="2015" course_id="108882" class_number="11398" school_id="fas" section="001" term_code="spring">
        <catalog_info>
            <title short_title="APPHY 50B">Physics as a Foundation for Science and Engineering, Part II</title>
            <notes> AP50b satisfies the premedical requirements and is equivalent in content and rigor to a standard introductory physics course for scientists and engineers (Physical Sciences 3, Physical Sciences 12b, Physics 15b), but focuses on the application of physics to real-world problems. This course, when taken for a letter grade, meets the General Education requirement for Science of the Physical Universe.</notes>
            <prereq>Recommended: A solid knowledge of multivariable calculus at the level of Applied Math 21a or Math 21a is required. Mathematics 21a can be taken concurrently.</prereq>
            <description>AP 50b is the second half of a one-year, team-based and project-based introduction to physics. This course teaches students to develop scientific reasoning and problem-solving skills. AP50b topics include: electrostatics; electric currents; magnetostatics; electromagnetic induction; Maxwell's Equations; electromagnetic radiation; geometric optics; and, wave optics. Multivariable and vector calculus is introduced and used extensively in the course. Students work in teams on three, month-long projects, each culminating in a project fair. The twice-weekly class periods are all inclusive: there are no separate labs or discussion sections.</description>
            <department code="APPHYS">Applied Physics</department>
            <course_group code="APPHY">Applied Physics</course_group>
            <course_type>Lecture</course_type>
            <credits>4</credits>
            <meeting_schedule>
                <meeting days_of_week="Tuesday Thursday" end_time="12:59:00" location="" start_time="10:00:00"/>
            </meeting_schedule>
        </catalog_info>
        <staff>
            <person id="d1e26125a1310" role="1" seniority_sort="1">
                <display_name>Eric Mazur</display_name>
            </person>
            <person id="d1e26128a1310" role="2" seniority_sort="2">
                <display_name>Kelly Miller</display_name>
            </person>
        </staff>
    </course>
</courses>