<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<courses>
    <course academic_year="2015" course_id="111301" class_number="14373" school_id="fas" section="001" term_code="fall">
        <catalog_info>
            <title short_title="CZCH AA">Elementary Czech I</title>
            <exam_group>FAS12_A</exam_group>
            <description>	Part one of a two part introductory course in modern Czech language and culture, designed for students without previous knowledge who would like to speak Czech or use the language for reading and research. All four major communicative skills (speaking, listening comprehension, reading, writing) are stressed. Students are exposed to Czech culture through work with film and literature and gain some familiarity with the major differences between literary and spoken Czech as they learn to use the language both as a means of communication and as a tool for reading and research. Czech AA: Elementary Czech I (in the fall) and Czech AB: Elementary Czech II (in the spring) satisfy the foreign language requirement and prepare students for continued study of Czech in intermediate-level courses and for study or travel abroad in the Czech Republic.	&amp;nbsp;	Please note that this course will also meet for an additional hour of speaking practice to be arranged the first week of classes. See language course notes on our website for information about sectioning, pass/fail, satisfactory/unsatisfactory, and auditing.&amp;nbsp;</description>
            <department code="SLAV">Slavic Languages and Literatures</department>
            <course_group code="CZCH">Czech</course_group>
            <course_type>Lecture</course_type>
            <credits>4</credits>
            <meeting_schedule>
                <meeting days_of_week="Monday Wednesday Friday" end_time="10:59:00" location="Barker 211 (FAS)" start_time="10:00:00"/>
            </meeting_schedule>
            <exam_date>2015-12-17</exam_date>
        </catalog_info>
        <staff>
            <person id="d1e163672a1310" role="1" seniority_sort="1">
                <display_name>Veronika Tuckerova</display_name>
            </person>
        </staff>
    </course>
</courses>