<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<courses>
    <course academic_year="2015" course_id="112107" class_number="10928" school_id="fas" section="001" term_code="fall">
        <catalog_info>
            <title short_title="PHYSICS 195">Introduction to Solid State Physics</title>
            <exam_group>FAS08_K</exam_group>
            <notes>Designed as a first course in solid state physics for students with knowledge of elementary quantum mechanics. Students who intend to take Applied Physics 295, and who have not previously taken a formal course in solid state physics, are strongly advised to take this course first.   Designed as a first course in solid state physics for students with knowledge of elementary quantum mechanics. 

Students who intend to take Applied Physics 295, and who have not previously taken a formal course in solid state physics, are strongly advised to take this course first.</notes>
            <prereq>Recommended: Elementary quantum mechanics.</prereq>
            <description>The physics of crystalline solids and their electric, magnetic, optical, and thermal properties. Designed as a first course in solid-state physics. Topics: free electron model; Drude model; the physics of crystal binding; crystal structure and vibration (phonons); electrons in solids and band formation; metals and semiconductors; diodes and transistors; plasmonic excitations and screening; optical properties; solid-state lasers; magnetism, spin waves, magnetic resonance, and spin-based devices; dielectrics and ferroelectrics; superconductivity, Josephson junctions, and superconducting circuits; electronic transport in low-dimensional systems, quantum Hall effect, and resonant tunneling devices.</description>
            <department code="PHYS">Physics</department>
            <course_group code="PHYSICS">Physics</course_group>
            <course_type>Lecture</course_type>
            <credits>4</credits>
            <meeting_schedule>
                <meeting days_of_week="Wednesday Friday" end_time="14:29:00" location="60 Oxford St 330" start_time="13:00:00"/>
            </meeting_schedule>
            <exam_date>2015-12-15</exam_date>
        </catalog_info>
        <staff>
            <person id="d1e67510a1310" role="1" seniority_sort="1">
                <display_name>Donhee Ham</display_name>
            </person>
        </staff>
    </course>
</courses>