<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<courses>
    <course academic_year="2015" course_id="159659" class_number="14444" school_id="fas" section="001" term_code="spring">
        <catalog_info>
            <title short_title="RUSS BTB">Intermediate Russian through Authentic Texts (Russian through Bulgakov II)</title>
            <prereq>Recommended: Russian Ba or Russian Bta, or placement into Bb/Btb. Familiarity with fundamentals of Russian grammar, particularly case endings of the noun, pronoun, and adjective and elementary competence in spoken Russian.</prereq>
            <description>Part two of a two part intermediate course in Russian language and culture through reading of what is arguably 20th-century Russia&amp;#39;s greatest novel, Mikhail Bulgakov&amp;#39;s&amp;nbsp;The Master and Margarita. This literary and linguistic approach to Intermediate Russian has a strong emphasis on reading authentic Russian, but all four major communicative skills (speaking, listening comprehension, reading, writing) are stressed as students learn to use the language both as a means of communication and as a tool for reading and research. Further development of vocabulary and oral expression within a comprehensive review of Russian grammar. Systematic study of word formation and other strategies are taught to help free students from excessive dependence on the dictionary and develop confidence in reading. Any full course in Russian at the B-level (Russian Ba-Bb, Russian Bta-Btb, or Intensive Russian Bab) will prepare students for continued study of Russian at the advanced level (Russian 101) and for study or travel abroad in Russian-speaking countries.Please see language course notes on our website for information about sectioning, pass/fail, satisfactory/unsatisfactory, auditing, and language track information.&amp;nbsp;</description>
            <department code="SLAV">Slavic Languages and Literatures</department>
            <course_group code="RUSS">Russian</course_group>
            <course_type>Lecture</course_type>
            <credits>4</credits>
            <meeting_schedule>
                <meeting days_of_week="Monday Wednesday Friday" end_time="09:59:00" location="" start_time="09:00:00"/>
            </meeting_schedule>
        </catalog_info>
        <staff>
            <person id="d1e175757a1310" role="1" seniority_sort="1">
                <display_name>Oksana Willis</display_name>
            </person>
        </staff>
    </course>
</courses>