<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<courses>
    <course academic_year="2015" course_id="159620" class_number="14403" school_id="fas" section="001" term_code="spring">
        <catalog_info>
            <title short_title="RUSS AB">Elementary Russian II</title>
            <description>Part two of a two part introductory course in modern Russian language and culture, designed for students without previous knowledge of Russian who would like to speak Russian or use the language for reading and research. All four major communicative skills (speaking, listening comprehension, reading, writing) are stressed. Students are introduced to Russian culture and the etiquette of social exchanges, and expand their knowledge of grammar and vocabulary through readings (including stories, biography, and poetry), videos, and class discussions.Russian Aa: Elementary Russian I together with Russian Ab: Elementary Russian II or Russian Atb: Elementary Russian through Authentic Texts II satisfy the foreign language requirement. Any of the elementary (A-level) level Russian courses (A, Aab, and At) prepare students for continued study of Russian in intermediate (B-level) courses (B, Bab, or Bt) and for study or travel abroad in Russian-speaking countries.Please note that this course will also meet for two additional hours of speaking practice to be arranged the first week of classes. See language course notes on our website for information about sectioning, pass/fail, satisfactory/unsatisfactory, auditing, and language track information.</description>
            <department code="SLAV">Slavic Languages and Literatures</department>
            <course_group code="RUSS">Russian</course_group>
            <course_type>Lecture</course_type>
            <credits>4</credits>
            <meeting_schedule>
                <meeting days_of_week="Monday Wednesday Friday" end_time="09:59:00" location="" start_time="09:00:00"/>
            </meeting_schedule>
        </catalog_info>
        <staff>
            <person id="d1e14486a1310" role="1" seniority_sort="1">
                <display_name>Steven Clancy</display_name>
            </person>
            <person id="d1e95819a1310" role="1" seniority_sort="2">
                <display_name>Natalia Chirkov</display_name>
            </person>
        </staff>
    </course>
</courses>