<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<courses>
    <course academic_year="2015" course_id="160660" class_number="16366" school_id="fas" section="001" term_code="spring">
        <catalog_info>
            <title short_title="MUSIC 15B">Harvard Glee Club</title>
            <notes> Audition required.  The course is graded SAT/UNSAT based on attendance and participation. This course may be taken repeatedly, but to receive credit the course must be taken in the Fall and Spring semesters consecutively. A maximum of four semesters (two years) may be counted as credit towards the degree.</notes>
            <description>Harvard Glee Club (TTBB Choir).&amp;nbsp; As the nation&amp;#39;s oldest collegiate chorus, the Glee Club is a tenor and bass ensemble exploring music written in the male chorus tradition. The Glee Club performs throughout the year, collaborating with arts groups on campus and at other universities, and across the world on annual tours. Through excellence in performance, student-management, education, community, tradition, and philanthropy, the Glee Club offers a unique musical experience for all members. The Glee Club frequently combines with the Collegium and the Choral Society, as well as the Harvard-Radcliffe Orchestra, to perform large-scale works. Students must complete both parts of this course (parts A and B) within the same academic year in order to receive credit.</description>
            <department code="MUSC">Music</department>
            <course_group code="MUSIC">Music</course_group>
            <course_type>Studio</course_type>
            <credits>4</credits>
            <meeting_schedule>
                <meeting days_of_week="Monday Wednesday" end_time="18:29:00" location="" start_time="16:15:00"/>
            </meeting_schedule>
        </catalog_info>
        <staff>
            <person id="d1e12782a1310" role="1" seniority_sort="1">
                <display_name>Andrew Clark</display_name>
            </person>
        </staff>
    </course>
</courses>