<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<courses>
    <course academic_year="2015" course_id="160751" class_number="17896" school_id="fas" section="001" term_code="fall">
        <catalog_info>
            <title short_title="EMR 124">Childhood, Adolescence, Youth and International Human Rights</title>
            <exam_group>FAS07_B</exam_group>
            <notes> This course is open to seniors with instructor consent.  

This course will meet at HKS in room L382. The first class meeting is on September 2nd. The course will also meet for one Friday, on September 4th.</notes>
            <description>The Child Protection sector now consists of a multitude of organizations that have an ever-increasing need to coordinate. The number of development and humanitarian Child Protection actors now spans United Nations agencies, human rights bodies, local, national and international nongovernmental organizations (NGOs), national and local governments, intergovernmental organizations (IGOs), bilateral governmental development and humanitarian agencies, small civil society organizations (CSOs), international financial institutions (IFIs), other multilateral institutions, advocacy groups, private foundations, and the private sector. The early parts of this course will focus on understanding the background, structure, roles and mandates of each type of organization. Later, students will have opportunities to engage with practicing professionals and their in-class colleagues in order to conceptualize and design new programs and policies. Students will work with and across departments, sectors and geographic regions on a range of contemporary global issues relevant to Child Protection. The art of communicating across and within organizations for the development and advancement of innovative, evidence-based programs and policies will be the capstone experience of the course. Jointly offered at Harvad Kennedy School as IGA-343M, Chan Harvard School of Public Health as GHP 508, and Harvard Law School as 2533.</description>
            <department code="EMR">Ethnicity, Migration, Rights</department>
            <course_group code="EMR">Ethnicity, Migration, Rights</course_group>
            <course_type>Seminar</course_type>
            <credits>4</credits>
            <meeting_schedule>
                <meeting days_of_week="Monday Wednesday" end_time="12:59:00" location="" start_time="11:45:00"/>
            </meeting_schedule>
            <exam_date>2015-12-15</exam_date>
        </catalog_info>
        <staff>
            <person id="d1e160724a1310" role="1" seniority_sort="1">
                <display_name>Jacqueline Bhabha</display_name>
            </person>
        </staff>
    </course>
</courses>